<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Blogging | Indrajit Chakrabarty]]></title>
  <link href="http://indyfromoz.github.io/blog/categories/blogging/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://indyfromoz.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-09T12:00:27+10:00</updated>
  <id>http://indyfromoz.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Indrajit Chakrabarty]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[indrajit.chakrabarty@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://indyfromoz.github.io/blog/2013/09/08/hello-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-08T22:21:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://indyfromoz.github.io/blog/2013/09/08/hello-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I started a <a href="http://indyfromoz.wordpress.com">blog</a> with Wordpress five years ago with the idea of sharing my travels as a developer, geek, technologist, etc. The blog has had more than 50,000 visits over the last five years, if you are one of them reading this post, thank you for visiting my blog.</p>

<p>After five years of using Wordpress as the blog engine and Akismet for keeping the spammers away, I wanted to try <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a> after seeing all the cool blogs using it and <a href="http://pages.github.com/">Github Pages</a> to host themselves. For programmers/developer/hackers who are always near a Mac or a PC, Octopress provides a lot of power in the hands of the author. Two commands below are enough to publish a blog post &ndash;</p>

<p><code>
$ rake generate
$ rake deploy
</code></p>

<p>The only drawback I see with this workflow is the risk of publishing a post that is not yet ready for general consumption. For now, I have modified the Rakefile to include a line with <code>published: false</code> in the <code>new_post</code> template.</p>

<p>In the next post, I will be listing a bunch of links to resources I found very useful in setting up this blog. I hope with this new blogging platform, I should be able to post more frequently than I have in the last five years.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
